Rick Farouni | Curriculum Vitae

Department of Psychology, The Ohio State University
☐ rfarouni@gmail.com
☐ http://rfarouni.github.io/

I am currently a doctoral candidate in quantitative psychology at the Ohio State University. I hold a master's degree in mathematical statistics. I have excellent skills in scientific computing and a strong background in machine learning, multivariate statistics, and Bayesian statistics. My research is focused on latent variable modelling and the statistical analysis of fMRI neuroimaging data. I am passionate about the open access movement in education, research, and academia and I am dedicated to rigorous science in the public interest.

Education

Academic Qualifications.

The Ohio State University

PhD in Quantitative Psychology

Advisor: Professor Robert Cudeck

Ohio, USA

2012–Present

The Ohio State University

Master of Science in Statistics [GPA 3.80/4]

The Ohio State University

Ohio, USA
2012-2014

The Ohio State UniversityOhio, USAMaster's Degree in Quantitative Psychology2012-2014

Thesis Project: 'Latent Variable Modelling of Categorical Item Responses in a Hierarchical Bayesian Framework'

The Pennsylvania State University

Bachelor's Degree in Psychology with High Distinction [GPA 3.93/4]

Pennsylvania, USA 2011-2012

Course Projects....

- Multivariate Statistics (STAT 7560): 'Retinotopic Mapping of the Human Visual Cortex Using Independent Component Analysis'
- Advanced Computational Statistics (STAT 7730): 'Bayesian Analysis of Noisy Images Using Markov Random Fields'
- **Statistical Consulting** (STAT 6750): 'Modelling Categorical Perception of Speech Sounds using Beta Regression'

Conference Presentations

\sim	Joint Statistical Meetings	Seattle
	Poster Title: Across-Subject Predictive Modeling of fMRI BOLD Responses to Faces	2015

Awards and Fellowships

_	Graduate Student Conference Presentation Award	
0	The Ohio State University	2015

The Center for Cognitive and Brain Sciences Summer Graduate Fellowship

The Ohio State University

2015

Project Proposal: 'Decoding the Pixels of the Face Image from the Voxels of fMRI BOLD Activity Patterns'

The Social and Behavioral Sciences Summer Fellowship

The Ohio State University 2014

University Fellowship

The Ohio State University 2012

Experience

Teaching Experience.

Graduate Teaching Associate

Ohio, USA

The Ohio State University

2013-present

Teaching Assistant for Psychology 2220: Data Analysis in Psychology

Test Preparation Instructor

Moscow, Russia

Instructor of the Graduate Management Admission Test (GMAT)

Moscow, Russia

2009-2012

Teacher of English as a Foreign Language Teacher of General and Academic English

2001-2009

Journal Review Service.....

Psychometrika Ad Hoc Reviewer

2015

Psychological Methods

Ad Hoc Reviewer

2016

Programming and Software Skills

- Programming Languages: Proficient in numerical and statistical computing languages. Comfortable working with and transitioning between Julia, R, Python, and Matlab depending on computing goals. Strong command of probabilistic programming languages such as **Stan** and **Venture** (to a lesser extent). Experienced in training deep learning models on GPUs using Caffe, MXNet, and Neon frameworks. Experienced in using neuroimaging analysis software such as Nipype, PyMVPA, FreeSurfer, Pycortex, SPM and FSL.
- Computing Tools and Software: Experience with a variety of technologies such as LATEX, Linux OS, Git. Basic knowledge in website development tools such as HTML, CSS, and Jekyll.
- Supercomputing: Good knowledge of running numerical analyses on the Ohio Supercomputer Center's main clusters.

Personal Details

- Country of Previous Residence: Russia (12 years)
- o Marital Status: Married
- o Interests and Hobbies: Evolutionary Biology, World Cuisines, Experimental Music
- Languages Spoken: English, Arabic, Russian, Spanish (limited)